bante my mind exhibits such a persistent
inclination towards seeking structure
and order I Delight in having a to-do list
order I Delight in having a to-do list
and specific goals as a constant source
of motivation and
security when I don't have such things
and instead of instead have chaos I
cannot even keep the precepts I think
that this is somehow a problem because I
should be able to stay steady without
structure and despite the
chaos please
help well yes eventually but you you can
you can stay steady despite the cha but
until then structure can help you now
obviously it's what you take that
structure to be is it just like Mindless
adhering to the uh observed norm and
requirements of your behavior or is it
the the structure of structuring your
day so that you can watch your
intentions correctly not resort to
coping mechanisms meditation techniques
but instead
actually stud the sutas study the sutas
in a in a in a in a in a systematic
manner so that you can then apply that
with some with some discipline around
your day-to-day activities so that that
structure is fine there's no problem
there but of course you know and you
would be recognizing that if you start
if you start applying it rightly you
would you would then start you would
also then begin to see that
um you shouldn't be depending on the
structures but that doesn't mean that
you you can't benefit from them
initially so it's not like oh I have not
developed my mind yet but I recognize
that I shouldn't depend on structure so
I'll just expose myself to Absolute
chaotic environment because I shouldn't
be moved well you shouldn't be moved if
you would have completed development of
the mind for which certain structure is
required gradual training is a form of
structure what you don't do first what
you don't do second what you do third
and so on like uh it takes it takes
gradual development uh which which is
already a a form of uh structuring your
practice now if by structure you mean
you need a daily
routine uh that's programmed hour by
hour and somebody telling you what to do
well then yeah you have to abandon that
because that is a way too
um well it basically does not translate
to the real
world when sickness and aging and death
and loss of the L one set set in um your
your kind of micromanaged environment in
which you were able to practice your
mindfulness and so on where everything
was controlled minute by minute that
does not translate but basically you
would be struggling to remain unmoved
because that environment requires quite
a uh wide basis of Maintenance where
nothing where nothing should go wrong in
many different areas so that you can
afford it's a basically privilege
privilege environment which you won't
have and uh if um if you only know how
to practice in that type of protected
environment you you don't know how to
practice so that's what I mean like the
they layers to the
structure is it the structure somebody
policing my every move and telling me to
stop or do it or is it the structure of
a gradual training both can be called
structures but they are obviously on
very different levels like one one uh
set of structure is very controlling too
controlling well it's not that's really
not the main issue the main issue is
that the the the former set this the set
of structure where everything is like
micromanaged and uh and ordered minute
by minute is a structure that's rooted
in avoidance of
responsibility you don't want to think
for yourself you don't want to endure
the doubt for yourself you don't want to
wonder what should I do next just give
it to me written set in stone on paper
the weight of the authority and I'll
just adhere to it because it's
easier and that structure is a structure
of the wrong
view but if your structure is the
structure around your daily activities
to support your taking up responsibility
and sense restraint and withdrawal from
the UN wholesome States that's a fine
that's a fine structure but you got to
be doing it doing it
yourself not relying on the on the world
to force it upon you not not relying on
the World to force upon you or to or to
do it for you taking up the the the
burden of the action cuz I suppose a
person will want to like find a teacher
which is a good thing who will tell me
what to do and I will submit so you want
to find a teacher so you can learn from
so that you can apply those things
yourself for yourself but yes for many
people finding a t-shir equals finding
an external authority to which I'll
commit so I don't have to think for
myself and it's uh that's I mean it's
the core of that type of structure is
avoiding responsibility and that is a
that is a prerequisite for successful
practice of dharm to have to take
responsibility so doesn't matter how
much effort you invest
subsequently upon that structure in
terms of practice you actually kill the
DAT its trots because there is no
responsibility that fundamental
level so you have to revert all the way
back abandon it and then restart